Guide to the Max J. and Ruth Clement Bond Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series V: Personal, 1914-1995
  - Subseries V.3: Financial, 1931-1994, Undated
    Financial documents, including income tax returns, bank account statements and checks, real estate information, receipts and bills, were extensively preserved. Although the financial material spans over sixty years, the bulk of the documents are from the 1950s and 1960s. The banks represented by cancelled checks and monthly statements include: the Alabama Exchange Bank and Tuskegee Institute Savings Bank of Tuskegee, Alabama; the Lincoln Bank & Trust Company of Louisville, Kentucky; Citizens Trust of Atlanta, Georgia; and the Whitney National Bank of New Orleans, Louisiana. Copies of income tax returns, although not inclusive, cover most of the years between 1961 and 1992. Also found here is extensive documentation regarding a rental property owned by the Bonds in Louisville, Kentucky.
    - Bank Statements and Checking Accounts
      - Cancelled Checks, 1939-1954, (7 Folders) (Box 37)
      - Check Book Stubs
        - 1946 (1) (Box 38)
        - 1949-1950 (2) (Box 38)
        - 1955-1956 (2) (Box 38)
        - 1960-1962 (1) (Box 38)
        - 1975-1994 (39) (Box 38)
    - General, 1943-1986 (Box 37)
    - Budget--Home, 1947-1949 (Box 37)
    - Expenses--Africa Trip 1978 (Box 37)
    - Income Tax Returns, 1940s 1961-1992, (3 Folders) (Box 37)
    - Life Insurance, 1931-1987 (Box 37)
    - Moving and Storage, 1945, 1950-1966 (Box 37)
    - Property Tax Appeal, 1975 (Box 37)
    - Rental Property--Louisville, Kentucky--Bills and Receipts, 1960s-1970s (Box 37)
    - Rental Property--Louisville, Kentucky--Documents and Correspondence, 1960s-1990, (3 Folders) (Box 37)
    - Rich's Department Store--Receipts, 1948-1950s (Box 37)
    - Tuskegee--Prairie Farms--Account Book, 1940-1941 (Box 37)
- Series VI: Photographs, 1912-1990s
  The bulk of the material in this series comprises personal and family photographs, as well as pictures from some of the many events hosted by one of the organizations with which the Bonds were affiliated, especially the Boys and Girls Club of Greater Washington. Also included are slides and photographs from trips abroad. These photographs, a mix of black and white, and color, were scattered throughout the collection with little discernable order. Most of them were loose and unidentified, yet there were also some albums and a few labeled photographs. Whenever possible, photographs found in the same location have been kept together. Easily identifiable material was arranged according to the people featured and the nature of the event.
  - General and Unidentified, Undated (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Albums
    - Family, 1920s-1980s (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - "Red Album"-- Professional, Undated, (2 Folders) (Box 39, Folder 3 to 4)
    - "White Album"--Personal, Undated (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Family
    - Emma C. Clement--Mother of the Year, 1946 (Box 41, Folder 11)
    - General, 1930s-1990s, Undated, (2 Folders) (Box 39, Folder 6 to 7)
    - Early Family Pictures, 1912, Undated (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - Friends and Family, 1940s-1980s, Undated, (2 Folders) (Box 39, Folder 9 to 10)
  - Ghana, Undated (Box 39, Folder 11)
  - Liberia, 1953-1954 (with labels) (Box 39, Folder 12)
  - Liberia--University of, Undated (Rolled) (Box 41, Folder 12)
  - Negatives, Undated (Box 39, Folder 13)
  - Organizations, 1950s-1980s, Undated (Box 39, Folder 14)
  - Professional, 1950s-1980s, Undated, (2 Folders) (Box 39, Folder 15 to 16)
  - Slides, 1958-1961 (Box 39, Folder 17)
    (Some Labeled)